peterlang.com 2019-06-03

# Privacy Policy for Website Visitors and Customers

## Click here to see privacy Policy for Authors, Contributors and Editors

Peter Lang AG (“Peter Lang”, “we”) operates the website peterlang.com (the “Site”), accessible at <https://www.peterlang.com/>. Through this privacy policy, we inform you on whatpersonal data we collect when you visit our Site and how we process it. With this privacy policy we also fulfil our duty to inform you pursuant to Art. 13 GDPR.

## 1\. Identity of the controller

The controller is the

Peter Lang AG  
International Academic Publishers  
Wabernstrasse 40  
CH-3007 Bern  
Schweiz

E-Mail: [info@peterlang.com](mailto:info@peterlang.com)

Tel. +41 (0)31 306 17 17  
Fax +41 (0)31 306 17 27

## 2\. When, how and why we process personal data

### 2.1 Personal data

Pursuant to the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR“), personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (‘data subject’). An identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification num-ber, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.

### 2.2 Which kind of data we process and how we collect it

#### 2.2.1 General use of the Site

Insofar as you do not actively make personal data available to us, we do not store personal data while you use our Site except that our webserver(s) register all connec-tions to the Site automatically and collects the following technical information about your visit:

  * Your IP address
  * the name of the files accessed;
  * information about the transmission;
  * date and time of the connection;
  * the amount of data transmitted;
  * the requesting provider;
  * the referrer; and
  * the web browser/user agent

#### 2.2.2 Registering for a user account

You may register for a user account on our Site. You need a user account in order to buy books or other content from our online shop. For creating a user account, we collect the following data:

  * Name
  * Username
  * Email address
  * Password

If you buy a product from our online shop, the respective content will be linked to your user account.

#### 2.2.3 Buying content

You can buy our products directly in our online shop as well as via mail, telephone or telefax. Additionally, to the data mentioned in Sec. 2.2.2, we need the following data to process your order:

  * Country
  * Street
  * House number
  * Postal code
  * City
  * Telephone number

#### 2.2.4 Contact

If you contact us by writing an email or using the respective form on the website, we collect your email address and all information that is included in the email.

### 2.3 Why and on which legal basis do we do that

We process your IP address only to allow your device to establish a connection to our webserver over the Internet. This processing is based on Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR.

If you register a user account with us, we process this data to create your user ac-count and manage all related operations, for example buying a book or other con-tent. The legal basis is Art. 6 part. 1 lit. b) GDPR.

If you buy a book or other content, we process the collected data for the purposes of performance and conclusion of contract. The legal basis is Art. 6 par. 1 lit. b) GDPR. Additionally, we are legally obliged to store certain data, which is included in contracts and invoices as well as in business letters or other documents relevant for taxation or accounting. The legal basis is Art. 6 par. 1 lit. c) GDPR.

If you contact us by email or by using a contact form, the processing is based on Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The purpose as well as our legitimate interest is to answer your inquiry.

## 3\. Who receives personal data from us and when it is transferred to third countries

Internally, the relevant department processes your data. Externally, we use IT service providers. Otherwise, we do not transfer data to third countries. Personal data may be shared with other affiliated companies in order to fulfill our contractual duties. Certain IT service providers we use reside in the U.S. We concluded Standard contrac-tual clauses with them in order to provide appropriate safeguards.

## 4\. Period for which personal data will be stored

The data processed in relation to your user account is stored until you terminate your user account. After termination, we delete your data immediately.

We store the data about your purchases as long as you have a user account with us. However, if personal data is stored in contracts or invoices, we store it until the end of the eleventh year after conclusion of contract. If personal data is stored in business letters or other documents relevant for taxation or accounting, we store it until the end of the eleventh year after conclusion of contract.

Your emails will be stored for the time needed to answer your inquiry and for 5 more years, if you refer to us again.

## 5\. Your rights as a data subject

If the respective requirements are met, the GDPR grants you certain rights as a data subject.

  * **Art. 15 GDPR – Right of access:** You shall have the right to obtain from us confirmation as to whether or not personal data concerning you are being processed, and, where that is the case, access to the personal data and certain information.
  * **Art. 16 GDPR – Right to rectification:** You shall have the right to obtain from us without undue delay the rectification of inaccurate personal data concern-ing you. Taking into account the purposes of the processing, you shall have the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement.
  * **Art. 17 GDPR – Right to erasure:** You shall have the right to obtain from us the erasure of personal data concerning you without undue delay.
  * **Art. 18 GDPR – Right to restriction of processing:** You shall have the right to obtain from us the restriction of processing.
  * **Art. 20 GDPR – Right to data portability:** You shall have the right to receive the personal data concerning you, which you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and you shall have the right to transmit those data to another controller without hindrance from us. You shall also have the right to have the personal data transmitted directly from us to another controller, where technically feasible.
  * **Art. 21 GDPR – Right to object:** You shall have the right to object, on grounds relating to your particular situation, at any time to processing of personal data concerning you, which is based on legitimate interests or for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the controller  
In such case, we shall no longer process the personal data unless we demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing, which override your interests, rights and freedoms or where the processing is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.
  * **Art. 77 GDPR – Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority:** Without prejudice to any other administrative or judicial remedy, you shall have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the Member State of your habitual residence, place of work or place of the alleged infringement if you consider that the processing of personal data relating to you infringes the GDPR.

Where the processing is based on your informed consent, you shall have the right to withdraw consent at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal. Therefore, you may send us a message to [info@peterlang.com](mailto:info@peterlang.com).

## 6\. Your obligation to provide us with personal data

You have no statutory or contractual obligation to provide us with any personal data. However, we may not be able to provide you with our services if you decide not to do so.

## 7\. Existence of automated decision-making, including profiling

We do not use automated decision-making, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affects you.

## 8\. Internet specific processing or use of personal data

### 8.1 Cookies

For providing you the services of the Site we may use cookies. Cookies are small text files, which are transferred from the Site and stored on your device. Cookies cannot execute programs or infect your device with computer viruses. We use cookies, to provide certain technical features to you, such as a shopping basket. The legal basis for this is Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR. Our legitimate interest is to provide you with the respective features.

If you wish to prevent us from storing cookies on your device, your web browser or device may provide you with certain settings to do so. Most web browsers accept cookies by default. However, you may change these default settings in order to prevent any kind of storage or only allow storage after an explicit request. You may find an instruction on how to change your settings in the help section of your browser or device. The respective settings only apply to the device you are currently using. If you use another device, change your web browser or reinstall your browser you may have to change the respective settings again. Please, be aware that not accepting cookies may lead to you not being able to fully use the Site. In particular, ordering products through the Site may not be possible without cookies. Our usage of cookies finds its legal basis in Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The aforementioned purposes constitute also the legitimate interests we pursue with it.

### 8.2 Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics, operated by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google“) to collect information about how users use our Site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the Site will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. As IP-anonymization is activated, your IP address will be anonymized as soon as technically feasible at the earliest possible stage of the collection network. In addition, it will only be partially used within the European Union or just in the European Economic Area if it is used by other parties. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address will be transferred to a Google server in the United States, and then shortened so it is only partially used there.

Google will use this information on our behalf for the purpose of analyzing your use of the Site, compiling reports on the website activity and providing other services re-lating to activity on the Site and internet usage. The IP address that your browser conveys within the scope of Google Analytics will not be associated with any other da-ta held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser; please note, however, that if you do this you may not be able to use our service comprehensively. You can also opt-out from being tracked by Google Analytics in the future by downloading and installing ‘Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on’ for your current web browser:   
<http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.

Our processing is based on Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The aforementioned purposes constitute also the legitimate interests we pursue with it. The collected data is stored for 26 months. Further information on how Google processes personal data is available at: <https://policies.google.com/?hl=en> .

### 8.3 Doubleclick

Doubleclick by Google is a service of the Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). Doubleclick by Google uses cookies to show you relevant advertising. Google will create a pseudonymous ID in order to store and analyse which ads were presented to you and on which ads you clicked. The cookies do not contain personal information. Using DoubleClick-Cookies, Google and its partners will show you targeted advertising. The information will be transferred to and stored on a server in the USA. Google takes part in the EU-US-Privacy-Shield pro-gram. You may prevent such collection and storage by enabling the respective set-tings in your browser software. However, using our website with all its features may no longer be possible.

You can also prevent the collection and storage by changing your preferences on the following site:   
<https://adssettings.google.com/u/0/authenticated?hl=de-DE>.

Our processing is based on Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The aforementioned purposes constitute also the legitimate interests we pursue with it. For more information on how Google processes your data, please refer to: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>.

### 8.4 New Relic

New Relic is a service of the New Relic Inc., 101 Second Street, 15th Floor, San Fran-cisco, CA 94105 (“New Relic”) that analyses the performance of our website. New Relic collects usage data and analyses the technical performance of our Site. This may contain information about add-ons, using times, your browser and about your hard- and software. New Relic uses cookies for this analysis. The data will be pro-cessed on a server in the U.S. in order to provide us with aggregated reports. New Relic also uses the data to compare the performance of different websites. New Relic is certified under the EU-US-Privacy Shield. Our processing is based on Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The aforementioned purposes constitute also the legitimate interests we pursue with it. You can object by setting the relevant preferences in your device’s software. Further information about the processing of data by New Relic is accessible on the following website: <http://newrelic.com/privacy>.

### 8.5 AddThis

We use so called social plugins („Plugins“) of AddThis. AddThis is operated by Oracle America, Inc. ("Oracle") located at 500 Oracle Parkway, Redwood Shores, CA 94065 („AddThis“). We use the Plugins for the purpose of enabling you to share our Site on and connect to your preferred social networks. If you visit our Site, your browser directly connects to the server of AddThis and transmits the Plugins contents to your device. AddThis collects the information that you visited our Site as well as your IP address and stores it on its servers in the USA. AddThis “tags” visitors on the websites that use AddThis Publisher Applications with browser cookies. This browser cookie tracks the content viewed by the visitor. Pixel tags are then used to transfer browsing data from you to AddThis and its partners. AddThis uses this data in order to create pseudonymous user profiles and to be able to provide interest-based advertising on websites using AddThis. We have no access to the data stored and processed by AddThis. For further information, please refer to: <http://www.addthis.com/privacy>. You can object the creation of pseudonymous usage profiles by opting out on the following website  
or by deleting and blocking the cookies from AddThis in your device’s software. Our processing is based on Art. 6 par. 1 lit. f) GDPR. The aforementioned purposes constitute also the legitimate interests we pursue with it.

Bern, May 2018

## **Privacy Policy for Authors, Contributors and Editors**

In compliance with our duty to furnish information pursuant to GDPR Art. 13, this Privacy Policy is to explain to you how we process the data you provide to us as an author, contributor or editor.

## 1\. Name and contact details of the data controller

The responsibility for the data lies with the company you have signed an author’s or editor’s agreement with. If you have contributed an article to a collected volume the responsibility lies with the company that the editor or editors of the collected volume have signed an agreement with. This can be one of the following companies:

### 1.1. Peter Lang AG  
International Academic Publishers

Wabernstrasse 40

CH-3007 Bern

Switzerland

E-Mail: info@peterlang.com

Tel. +41 (0)31 306 17 17

Fax +41 (0)31 306 17 27

### 1.2. P.I.E. - Peter Lang SA  
Éditions Scientifiques Internationales

1 avenue Maurice, 6e étage

1050 Brussels

Belgium

E-Mail: info@peterlang.com

Tel. +32 (0)2 347 72 36

Fax +32 (0)2 347 72 37

### 1.3. Peter Lang Ltd  
International Academic Publishers

52 St Giles

Oxford

OX1 3LU

United Kingdom

E-Mail: info@peterlang.com

Tel. +44 (0)1865 514160

Fax +44 (0)1865 604028

### 1.4. Peter Lang Publishing Inc.

29 Broadway, 18th floor

New York, NY 10006 

USA

E-Mail: info@peterlang.com

Tel. +1 (212) 647-7706

Fax +1 (212) 647-7707

### 1.5. Peter Lang GmbH  
International Academic Publishers

Schlüterstrasse 42

10707 Berlin

Germany

E-Mail: info@peterlang.com

Tel. +49 (0) 30 232 567 900

Fax +49 (0) 30 232 567 902

The contact details of the data protection officer of the Peter Lang GmbH are:

Thorsten Feldmann

JBB Rechtsanwälte

Christinenstrasse 18/19

10119 Berlin

Email: feldmann@jbb.de

## 2\. Author and editor relationship management when a book is published

If you have concluded an author’s or editor’s agreement with us concerning the publication of a book, we process your data in the manner described below. 

### 2.1. Categories of data processed

We process the following of your personal data:

  * Name
  * Postal address (private)
  * Postal address (business)
  * Telephone number
  * Fax
  * Email address
  * Bank data
  * Tax ID
  * VAT liability
  * Addresses differing from billing address
  * Delivery address
  * Accounting information
  * Dunning levels
  * Delivery blocks
  * Customer block
  * Printing cost subsidies

### 2.2.   Purposes and lawfulness of processing

In the context of general author and editor relationship management, we use said data for the purpose of publishing the book. Specifically, this covers the drafting of the contract, payment, and general performance of the publishing contract. The lawful basis for this is to be found in GDPR Art. 6(1) point b).

Finally, we store your data for accounting and tax purposes. This is done on the basis of GDPR Art. 6(1) point c).

### 2.3.   Recipients or categories of recipients of personal data

For the purposes of author and editor relationship management, your data is processed by departments within the company you have signed an author’s or editor’s agreement with. These may include, for example:

  * Editorial department,
  * Production department,
  * Accounting department,
  * IT department,
  * Sales department,
  * Marketing department.

Moreover, to the extent necessary we also transfer the data to external parties. In addition to our technical service providers, these include:

  * Series editors
  * Proofreading and copy-editing services
  * Printers
  * Shipping services
  * Delivery services
  * Group companies

### 2.4.   Data transfers to third countries

We transfer data to our group company in Switzerland. Switzerland is a so-called safe third country recognised by the EU Commission, so an adequate level of protection of your personal data is ensured. In addition, we send manuscripts to a provider who offers proofreading, typesetting and layout services; this provider is based in India. We also use the services of an IT provider in the USA for operating our website.

### 2.5.   Storage period

The following data is stored for the term of the underlying author’s or editor’s agreement, and for a further 11 years commencing on closure of the year during which the agreement terminated:

  * Name
  * Postal address (private)
  * Postal address (business)
  * Telephone number
  * Fax
  * Email address
  * Bank data
  * Tax ID
  * VAT liability
  * Addresses differing from billing address
  * Delivery address
  * Accounting information
  * Dunning levels
  * Delivery blocks
  * Customer block
  * Printing cost subsidies

## 3\. Series editor relationship management

If you have concluded a series editor contract with us concerning the supervision of a book series, we process your data in the manner described below.

### 3.1. Categories of data processed

We process the following of your personal data:

  * Name
  * Postal address (private)
  * Postal address (business)
  * Telephone number
  * Fax
  * Email address
  * Bank data
  * Tax ID
  * VAT liability
  * Addresses differing from billing address
  * Delivery address
  * Accounting information

### 3.2. Purposes and lawfulness of processing 

We use said data for the purpose of general series editor relationship management. Specifically, this covers the drafting of the contract, payment, and general performance of the contract. The lawful basis for this is to be found in GDPR Art. 6(1) point b).

Finally, we store your data for accounting and tax purposes. This is done on the basis of GDPR Art. 6(1) point c).

### 3.3. Recipients or categories of recipients of personal data

For the purposes of series editor relationship management, your data is processed by departments within the company you have signed a series editor’s agreement with. These may include, for example:

  * Editorial department,
  * Production department,
  * Accounting department,
  * IT department,
  * Sales department,
  * Marketing department.

Moreover, to the extent necessary we also transfer the data to external parties. In addition to our technical service providers, these include:

  * Proofreading and copy-editing services
  * Printers
  * Shipping services
  * Delivery services
  * Group companies

### 3.4.   Data transfers to third countries

We transfer data to our group company in Switzerland. Switzerland is a so-called safe third country recognised by the EU Commission, so an adequate level of protection of your personal data is ensured. In addition, we send manuscripts to a provider who offers proofreading, typesetting and layout services; this provider is based in India. We also use the services of an IT provider in the USA for operating our website.

### 3.5.   Storage period

The following data is stored for the term of the underlying editor’s agreement, and for a further 11 years commencing on closure of the year during which the agreement terminated:

  *  
  * Name
  * Postal address (private)
  * Postal address (business)
  * Telephone number
  * Fax
  * Email address
  * Bank data
  * Tax ID
  * VAT liability
  * Addresses differing from billing address
  * Delivery address
  * Accounting information

## 4\. Publication of an article in a collected volume

If you have contributed an article to a collected volume which we publish, we process your data in the following manner.

### 4.1.  Categories of data processed

We process the following of your personal data:

  * Name
  * Postal address
  * Telephone number
  * Fax
  * Email address

### 4.2. Purposes and lawfulness of processing

We use said data for the purpose of publishing your article. The lawful basis for this is to be found in GDPR Art. 6(1) point b).

Finally, we store your data for accounting and tax purposes. This is done on the basis of GDPR Art. 6(1) point c).

### 4.3. Recipients or categories of recipients of personal data

Your data is processed by departments within the company that the editor or editors of the collected volume you have contributed an article to have signed an agreement with. These may include, for example:

  * Editorial department,
  * Production department,
  * IT department,
  * Sales department,
  * Marketing department.

Moreover, to the extent necessary we also transfer the data to external parties. In addition to our technical service providers, these include:

  * Proofreading and copy-editing services
  * Printers
  * Shipping services
  * Delivery services
  * Group companies

### 4.4. Data transfers to third countries

We transfer data to our group company in Switzerland. Switzerland is a so-called safe third country recognised by the EU Commission, so an adequate level of protection of your personal data is ensured. In addition, we send manuscripts to a provider who offers proofreading, typesetting and layout services; this provider is based in India. We also use the services of an IT provider in the USA for operating our website.

### 4.5. Storage period 

The following data is stored for the term of the underlying editor’s agreement, and for a further 11 years commencing on closure of the year during which the agreement terminated:

  * Name
  * Postal address
  * Telephone number
  * Fax
  * Email address

## 5\. Marketing

As a business, we naturally want to keep you informed and up-to-date about our newest products and latest offers.

### 5.1. Categories of data processed

We process the following of your personal data:

  * Name
  * Postal address
  * Telephone number
  * Fax
  * Email address
  * Advertising stop
  * Job title
  * Company membership
  * Affiliation
  * Faculty membership
  * Language
  * Title
  * Usage history (mail clicked, opened or not)

### 5.2.   Purposes and lawfulness of processing

We process your data to send you information about products, business models and topical matters. The lawful basis for this is to be found in GDPR Art. 6(1) points a) and f). Our legitimate interest in this respect is doing direct advertising.

### 5.3.   Recipients or categories of recipients of personal data

Your data is processed by departments within the company you have signed an author’s or editor’s agreement with. If you have contributed an article to a collected volume your data is processed by departments of the company that the editor or editors of the collected volume have signed an agreement with. These may include, for example:

  * IT department,
  * Sales department,
  * PR department,
  * Marketing department.

Moreover, to the extent which our marketing activities require, we also transfer your data to our group companies.

### 5.4. Data transfers to third countries

In some cases, e.g. in connection with events in third countries, advertising materials which contain your personal data may have to be sent to the third country concerned. In each case, this is done solely to advertise your own works in your own interest.

### 5.5. Storage period

Whenever processing is done on the basis of consent, your data will be stored as long as you do not withdraw your consent. If you do withdraw consent, then we will immediately stop sending you advertising and your data will be erased.

If processing is done for the purposes of a legitimate interest, your data will be erased after 5 years, unless you object to processing being done. In that case, we will of course immediately stop sending you advertising, but your data will not be erased until later (6 months later at the latest). 

## 6\. Rights of the data subject

The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) guarantees you rights which you may assert against us, provided the statutory requirements are met.

  * GDPR Art. 15 – Right of access by the data subject: You have the right to obtain confirmation from us as to whether or not personal data concerning yourself is being processed, and, where that is the case, which data is being processed and how.
  * GDPR Art. 16 – Right to rectification: You have the right to obtain from us without undue delay the rectification of inaccurate personal data concerning yourself. Taking into account the purposes of the processing, you also have the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement.
  * GDPR Art. 17 – Right to erasure: You have the right to obtain from us the erasure of personal data concerning yourself without undue delay.
  * GDPR Art. 18 – Right to restriction of processing: You have the right to obtain from us restriction of processing.
  * GDPR Art. 20 – Right to data portability: If processing is based on consent or on a contract, you have the right to receive the personal data concerning yourself which you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, and have the right to transmit that data to another controller without hindrance from us, or to have the personal data transmitted directly to another controller where technically feasible.
  * GDPR Art. 21 – Right to object: You have the right to object, on grounds relating to your particular situation, at any time to processing of personal data concerning yourself which is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us, or for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority.

If you file an objection, we will no longer process your personal data unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or processing is done for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

Where we process your personal data for direct marketing purposes, you have the right to object at any time to such processing. Where you object to processing for direct marketing purposes, your personal data will no longer be processed for such purposes.

  * GDPR Art. 77 in conjunction with the German Federal Data Protection Act. § 19 – Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority: You have the right to lodge a complaint at any time with a supervisory authority, in particular in the Member State of your habitual residence, place of work or place of the alleged infringement, if you consider that the processing of the personal data relating to yourself infringes applicable law.

If you have granted us consent, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. The withdrawal of consent will not affect the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal. For this purpose, you can send us a message at info@peterlang.com.

## 7\. Statutory and contractual obligation to provide data

You are under no obligation at any time to give us any data. However, if you do not provide us with the above-listed data for the respective processing purpose, we will not be in a position to conclude a contract with you or, where a contract has already been signed, to perform it. If you do not provide us with your data for direct marketing, we will no longer be able to inform you about our products, services and topical matters.

## 8\. Automated decision-making incl. profiling

We do not use automated decision-making which produces any legal effects for you, or which negatively affects you in any way.
